A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Office of the Secretary of Education, 1994; 1998-2006
Library of Virginia
- VI. Special Projects and Governor's Initiatives, 2001-2006., Extent: 17.20 cubic feet (49 boxes). (Box 89-136)
  - Subseries VI.A. Higher Education, 2001-2006., Extent: 5.60 cubic feet. (Box 89-104)
    Governor Warner vetoed legislation in April 2003 (HB2239) that claimed to prohibit undocumented students from receiving in-state tuition at Virginia's colleges and universities. Notable documents filed under Undocumented Aliens and In-State Tuition include: correspondence, legislation, talking points, meeting notes, articles, e-mail, reports, memorandums, and studies on this issue. Records are arranged in roughly reverse chronological order.
    - General Obligation Bonds (GOB) for Higher Education, 2001-2002
      - Virginia Business Higher Education Council, 2001 (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Building Virginia's Future, A Capital Improvement Plan, 7 January 2002 (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - SCHEV, 2002 GOB Referendum Pre-Planning Meeting, 17 April 2002 (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - General Obligation Bonds, Records, 2002 (Box 89, Folder 4)
      - Building a Better Future, General Obligation Bond Referendum, 2002 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Governor's Higher Education Summit, 2002-2003
      - February 2002 - May 2002 (Box 89, Folder 6)
      - Governor's Higher Education summit, Steering Committee Meeting, 30-31 May 2002 (Box 90, Volume Volume)
      - May 2002 - February 2003 (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - Planning Session for the Governor's Retreat with College and University Presidents, 22 March 2003 (Box 90, Folder 2)
      - Meeting with Council of Presidents, 15 April 2003 (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - Higher Education Research Summit, 1 May 2003 (part one) (Box 90, Folder 4)
      - Higher Education Research Summit, 1 May 2003 (part two) (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - College and University Research, 2002-2006
      - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 91, Folder 2)
      - Governor Mark R. Warner's Higher Education Research Summit, 1 May 2003 (Box 91, Folder 3)
      - Governor Mark R. Warner's Higher Education Research Summit, 1 May 2003 (part one) (Box 91, Folder 4)
      - Governor Mark R. Warner's Higher Education Research Summit, 1 May 2003 (part two) (Box 91, Folder 5)
      - Governor Mark R. Warner's Higher Education Research Summit, 1 May 2003 (part one) (Box 91, Folder 6)
      - Governor Mark R. Warner's Higher Education Research Summit, 1 May 2003 (part two) (Box 92, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 92, Folder 2)
      - Governor's Research Panel, Assessment of Virginia's College and University Research Programs, 5-7 October 2003 (Box 92, Folder 3)
      - Governor's Research Panel, Program Assessments and Institutional Responses, 14 November 2003 (Box 92, Folder 4)
      - Governor's Research Panel, Program Assessments and Institutional Responses, 14 November 2003 (Box 92, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 2003-2005 (Box 92, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, 2005 (Box 93, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 2005-2006 (Box 93, Folder 2)
      - Curriculum Vitas for Governor's Research Panel, ca. 2003 (Box 93, Folder 3)
      - University Profiles, 2003 (Box 93, Folder 4)
      - Institutional Presentations, Engineering and Materials I, 5-7 October 2003 (part one) (Box 93, Folder 5)
      - Institutional Presentations, Engineering and Materials I, 5-7 October 2003 (part two) (Box 93, Folder 6)
      - Institutional Presentations, Engineering and Materials I, 5-7 October 2003 (part three) (Box 93, Folder 7)
      - Institutional Presentations, Engineering and Materials II, 5-7 October 2003 (part one) (Box 94, Folder 1)
      - Institutional Presentations, Engineering and Materials II, 5-7 October 2003 (part two) (Box 94, Folder 2)
      - Institutional Presentations, Engineering and Materials II, 5-7 October 2003 (part three) (Box 94, Folder 3)
      - Institutional Presentations, Life and Medical Sciences, 5-7 October 2003 (part one) (Box 94, Folder 4)
      - Institutional Presentations, Life and Medical Sciences, 5-7 October 2003 (part two) (Box 94, Folder 5)
      - Institutional Presentations, Earth and Environmental Science, 5-7 October 2003 (part one) (Box 95, Folder 1)
      - Institutional Presentations, Earth and Environmental Science, 5-7 October 2003 (part two) (Box 95, Folder 2)
      - Institutional Presentations, Earth and Environmental Science, 5-7 October 2003 (part three) (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Higher Education Restructuring, 2002-2005
      - Higher Education Decentralization Initiative, 2001-2003, nd (Box 95, Folder 4)
      - Higher Education Regional Meetings, 2003-2005 (Box 95, Folder 5)
      - Governor's Higher Education Summit (Peter Blake), 2002 (Box 96, Folder 1)
      - National Collaborative for Postsecondary Education Policy (ECS), 2003 (Box 96, Folder 2)
      - Charter University Proposal/Higher Education Reform Act of 2005, 2004-2005 (part one) (Box 96, Folder 3)
      - Charter University Proposal/Higher Education Reform Act of 2005, 2004-2005 (part two) (Box 96, Folder 4)
      - Charter University Proposal, Legislative Package, 2003-2004 (part one) (Box 96, Folder 5)
      - Charter University Proposal, Legislative Package, 2003-2004 (part two) (Box 97, Folder 1)
      - Charter University Proposal, Legislative Package, 2003-2004 (part three) (Box 97, Folder 2)
      - Charter University Initiative, 2004 (part one) (Box 97, Folder 3)
      - Charter University Initiative, 2004 (part two) (Box 97, Folder 4)
      - Charter University Initiative, 2004 (part three) (Box 97, Folder 5)
      - Charter University Initiative, Background Material, nd (Box 97, Folder 6)
      - Charter University Initiative, Background Material, 2005 (part one) (Box 98, Folder 1)
      - Charter University Initiative, Background Material, 2005 (part two) (Box 98, Folder 2)
      - Charter University Initiative, Correspondence, 2003-2005 (Box 98, Folder 3)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part one) (Box 98, Folder 4)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part two) (Box 98, Folder 5)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part three) (Box 98, Folder 6)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part four) (Box 99, Folder 1)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part five) (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part six) (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part seven) (Box 99, Folder 4)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part eight) (Box 99, Folder 5)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part nine) (Box 100, Folder 1)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part ten) (Box 100, Folder 2)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part eleven) (Box 100, Folder 3)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part twelve) (Box 100, Folder 4)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part thirteen) (Box 100, Folder 5)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part fourteen) (Box 101, Folder 1)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part fifteen) (Box 101, Folder 2)
      - Restructuring and Performance Measures, 2005 (part sixteen) (Box 101, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous, 2005 (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - New College Institute, 2004-2005
      - Records, 2005 (part one) (Box 101, Folder 5)
      - Records, 2005 (part two) (Box 101, Folder 6)
      - Records, 2005 (part three) (Box 102, Folder 1)
      - Records, 2005 (part four) (Box 102, Folder 2)
      - Records, 2005 (part five) (Box 102, Folder 3)
      - Records, 2005 (part six) (Box 102, Folder 4)
      - Records, 2005 (part seven) (Box 102, Folder 5)
      - Records, 2005 (part eight) (Box 102, Folder 6)
      - Records, 2004-2005 (part nine) (Box 103, Folder 1)
      - Records, 2004-2005 (part ten) (Box 103, Folder 2)
      - Records, 2004-2005 (part eleven) (Box 103, Folder 3)
      - New College of Virginia, Briefing Book, 2004-2005 (part one) (Box 103, Folder 4)
      - New College of Virginia, Briefing Book, 2004-2005 (part two) (Box 103, Folder 5)
      - Oversize Records, 2005 (Box 103a)
    - Undocumented Aliens and In-State Tuition, 2002-2003
      - Records, 2003 (part one) (Box 104, Folder 1)
      - Records, 2003 (part two) (Box 104, Folder 2)
      - Records, 2003 (part three) (Box 104, Folder 3)
      - Records, 2002 (part four) (Box 104, Folder 4)
      - Records, 2002 (part five) (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Subseries VI.B. Education for a Lifetime Initiative, 2002-2005., Extent: 7.35 cubic feet. (Box 104-125)
    This subseries is housed in 21 boxes and is arranged by various aspects of the Education for a Lifetime Initiative. Governor Mark R. Warner's Education for a Lifetime initiative was a series of targeted reforms to improve a number of elements within the broad spectrum of "public education" including: Pre-Kindergarten (School Readiness Indicators), Accountability and Efficiency Reviews, Senior Year Plus (Path to Industry Certification), Teacher Support and Retention (Effective Mentoring and Turnaround Specialists), Preserving and Strengthening Higher Education, and Workforce Development (Race to GED and Career Readiness Certificates). The Education for a Lifetime Initiative was developed in 2002 and early 2003 and announced in September and October 2003. This subseries documents the development and implementation of various aspects of this wide ranging program. Most of the materials in this subseries are the records of Sarah Hopkins Finley, Deputy Secretary of Education. Subseries contains articles, agendas, correspondence, e-mail, meeting notes, executive issue briefs, recommendations, reports, surveys, memorandums, lists, presentations, budget documents, summaries, talking points, and legislation.
    The Warner Administration developed three Working Groups (Accountability, Needs, and Financing) consisting of various education experts and stakeholders whose purpose was the development of valuable information for the formulation of an action and legislative agenda for public education in Virginia (accountability, unmet education needs and funding as they related to K-12 system). The Accountability Work Group examined what Virginia was doing to help low performing schools, noting what worked and what more need to be done to ensure their success. The Needs Work Group helped identify the most pressing educational needs that affect the achievement levels for students. The Finance Work Group looked at how Virginia could pay for the things needed. Records include membership lists, meeting notes, correspondence, surveys, reports, e-mail for the Accountability and Needs Working Groups.
    The Education for a Lifetime, K-12 Plan was announced in September 2003. Notable records include: Education for a Lifetime Talking Points, September 2003 rollout (Pre-K, Project Graduation (SOL Remediation), Efficiency Reviews, Senior Year, Teacher Retention, and Higher Education (Box 108, Folder 5); Notes of K-20 Plan Development (Box 109, Folder 1); Governor's Meeting with Virginia Association of School Superintendents, 12 May 2003 (Box 109, Folder 2); Governor's Meeting with University Presidents, 15 April 2003 (Box 109, Folder 2); and Virginia Education Coalition Meeting with Governor, 5 May 2003 (Box 109, Folder 2).
    Other significant materials about the initiative may be found in the following areas: E arly Childhood Initiatives, Path to Industry Certification, Career and Technical Education, School Efficiency Reviews and Work Plans and Status Reports. The Work Plans and Status Reports are the records of Secretary of Education Belle Wheelan. The Higher Education, 2003 and Education Plan, K-12, 2003, materials provide an excellent, detailed, overview of the creation and implementation of the entire Education for a Lifetime Initiative (B123-B124).
    - K-12 Accountability Workgroup, 2002
      - Records, 2002 (part one) (Box 104, Folder 6)
      - Records, 2002 (part two) (Box 105, Folder 1)
      - Records, 2002 (part three) (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - K-12 Needs Workgroup, 2002-2003
      - Records, 2002-2003 (part one) (Box 105, Folder 3)
      - Records, 2002 (part two) (Box 105, Folder 4)
      - Records, 2002 (part three) (Box 105, Folder 5)
      - Records, 2002 (part four) (Box 105, Folder 6)
      - Records, 2002 (part five) (Box 106, Folder 1)
      - Records, 2002 (part six) (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - K-12 Working Groups, 2002
      - Records, 2002 (part one) (Box 106, Folder 3)
      - Records, 2002 (part two) (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - K-12 Needs Workgroup, 2002
      - Fairfax Meeting, 19 November 2002 (part one) (Box 106, Folder 5)
      - Fairfax Meeting, 19 November 2002 (part two) (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - K-12 Needs Workgroup - School Construction, 2002
      - Records, 2002 (part one) (Box 107, Folder 1)
      - Records, 2002 (part two) (Box 107, Folder 2)
      - Records, 2002 (part three) (Box 107, Folder 3)
      - Records, 2002 (part four) (Box 107, Folder 4)
      - Records, 2002 (part five) (Box 107, Folder 5)
      - Records, 2002 (part six) (Box 107, Folder 6)
      - Records, 2002 (part seven) (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - K-12 Accountability Workgroup, 2002
      - Rewards, Sanctions and Assistance Modes, Selected States, 2002, AEL (part one) (Box 108, Folder 1)
      - Rewards, Sanctions and Assistance Modes, Selected States, 2002, AEL (part two) (Box 108, Folder 2)
      - Records, 2002 (part one) (Box 108, Folder 3)
      - Records, 2002 (part two) (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - Education for a Lifetime, K-12 Plan, 2003
      - Records, 2003 (part one) (Box 108, Folder 5)
      - Records, 2003 (part two) (Box 109, Folder 1)
      - Records, 2003 (part three) (Box 109, Folder 2)
      - Records, 2003 (part four) (Box 109, Folder 3)
      - Records, 2003 (part five) (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - Joint Study - Use of Independent Education Performance Assessment, 2002-2003
      - Records, 2002-2003 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - Standard and Poors - Just for Kids, 2003
      - Records, 2003 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Governor's Senior Year Proposal, 2003
      - Records, 2003 (part one) (Box 110, Folder 2)
      - Records, 2003 (part two) (Box 110, Folder 3)
      - Records, 2003 (part three) (Box 110, Folder 4)
      - Records, 2003 (part four) (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Work Plans, 2003-2004
      - Records, 2003-2004 (part one) (Box 110, Folder 6)
      - Records, 2003-2004 (part two) (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Race to GED
      - Records, 2004 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Teacher Incentive Pilot - Development, 2004
      - Records, 2004 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Turnaround Specialist, 2004
      - Records, 2004 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Effective Mentoring - Development, 2003-2004
      - Records, 2003-2004 (part one) (Box 111, Folder 5)
      - Records, 2003-2004 (part two) (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Great Virginia Teach-In: A Call to Teach, 2003-2004
      - Records, 2003-2004 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Electronic Job Bank, 2003-2004
      - Records, 2003-2004 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - Project Graduation, 2003-2004
      - Records, 2003-2004 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Teacher Retention Initiative, 2003
      - Records, 2003 (part one) (Box 112, Folder 3)
      - Records, 2003 (part two) (Box 112, Folder 4)
      - Records, 2003 (part three) (Box 112, Folder 5)
      - Records, 2003 (part four) (Box 112, Folder 6)
      - Records, 2003 (part five) (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - Teacher Mentoring, 2003-2005
      - Virginia Mentor Teacher Institute, 17-18 June 2003 (Box 113, Folder 1)
      - Virginia Mentor Teacher Institute, 12-13 August 2004 (Box 113, Folder 2)
      - Virginia Mentor Teacher Institute, 24 June 2005 (Box 113, Folder 3)
      - Evaluation of Teacher Mentoring Programs, 2005 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - [Pre-Kindergarten] School Readiness Indicators, 2002-2004
      - Records, 2004 (part one) (Box 113, Folder 5)
      - Records, 2003-2004 (part two) (Box 113, Folder 6)
      - Records, 2003 (part three) (Box 113, Folder 7)
      - Records, 2003 (part four) (Box 114, Folder 1)
      - Records, 2002-2003 (part five) (Box 114, Folder 2)
      - Records, 2002 (part six) (Box 114, Folder 3)
      - Records, 2002-2003 (part seven) (Box 114, Folder 4)
    - Early Childhood Initiative, 2003-2005
      - Records, 2003 (Box 114, Folder 5)
      - Head Start, 2003 (Box 114, Folder 6)
      - Head Start, 2004 (Box 114, Folder 7)
      - Virginia's Early Learning Council, 2005 (part one) (Box 115, Folder 1)
      - Virginia's Early Learning Council, 2005 (part two) (Box 115, Folder 2)
      - Governor's Early Childhood Initiatives, 2005 (Box 115, Folder 3)
      - Governor's Early Childhood Initiatives and Healthy Virginias, 2005 (Box 115, Folder 4)
      - Virginia Early Childhood Comprehensive Systems (VECCS), 2004-2005 (part one) (Box 115, Folder 5)
      - Virginia Early Childhood Comprehensive Systems (VECCS), 2004-2005 (part two) (Box 115, Folder 6)
    - Path to Industry Certification, 2002-2005
      - Virginia Council for Career and Technical Education, 2002-2003 (part one) (Box 116, Folder 1)
      - Virginia Council for Career and Technical Education, 2002-2003 (part two) (Box 116, Folder 2)
      - Virginia Council for Career and Technical Education, 2002-2003 (part three) (Box 116, Folder 3)
      - CTE - Safety (Dept. of Education and Dept. of Labor), 2004-2005 (Box 116, Folder 4)
      - CTE - Path to Industry Certification, 2005 (part one) (Box 116, Folder 5)
      - CTE - Path to Industry Certification, 2005 (part two) (Box 116, Folder 6)
      - CTE - Path to Industry Certification, 2005 (part three) (Box 117, Folder 1)
      - Records, 2005 (Box 117, Folder 2)
      - Construction Trades Task Force, Heavy Equipment, 2004-2005 (Box 117, Folder 3)
      - Governor's Construction Task Force, 2004-2005 (part one) (Box 117, Folder 4)
      - Governor's Construction Task Force, 2004-2005 (part two) (Box 117, Folder 5)
      - Governor's Construction Task Force, 2004-2005 (part three) (Box 117, Folder 6)
      - Governor's Construction Task Force, 2004-2005 (part four) (Box 118, Folder 1)
      - Governor's Construction Task Force, 2004-2005 (part five) (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Career and Technical Education, 2002-2005
      - HJR 713 - Workforce Development, VDOE Adult Education, 2005 (Box 118, Folder 3)
      - General Notes/Studies, 2003 (part one) (Box 118, Folder 4)
      - General Notes/Studies, 2003 (part two) (Box 118, Folder 5)
      - General Notes/Studies, 2003 (part three) (Box 118, Folder 6)
      - Adult Education, 2002-2003 (Box 119, Folder 1)
      - Board of Education Advisory Committee for Career and Technical Education, 2003-2004 (Box 119, Folder 2)
      - Legislative Advisory Council on Career and Technical Education, 2002-2003 (part one) (Box 119, Folder 3)
      - Legislative Advisory Council on Career and Technical Education, 2002-2003 (part two) (Box 119, Folder 4)
      - Workforce Development, 2002-2003 (part one) (Box 119, Folder 5)
      - Workforce Development, 2002-2003 (part two) (Box 119, Folder 6)
      - Career and Technical Programs, 2002-2003 (Box 120, Folder 1)
      - Career and Technical Records, 2003 (part one) (Box 120, Folder 2)
      - Career and Technical Records, 2002-2003 (part two) (Box 120, Folder 3)
      - Career and Technical Records, 2002-2003 (part three) (Box 120, Folder 4)
      - Career and Technical Records, 2002-2003 (part four) (Box 120, Folder 5)
      - Career and Technical Records, 2002-2003 (part five) (Box 120, Folder 6)
      - Career and Technical Records, 2002-2004 (part six) (Box 121, Folder 1)
      - Career and Technical Records, 2002-2004 (part seven) (Box 121, Folder 2)
      - Career and Technical Records, 2002-2004 (part eight) (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - School Efficiency Reviews, 2002-2005
      - School Efficiency Reviews, 2004-2005 (part one) (Box 121, Folder 4)
      - School Efficiency Reviews, 2004-2005 (part two) (Box 121, Folder 5)
      - School Efficiency Reviews, 2004-2005 (part three) (Box 121, Folder 6)
      - School Efficiency Reviews, 2004-2005 (part four) (Box 122, Folder 1)
      - School Efficiency Reviews, 2004-2005 (part five) (Box 122, Folder 2)
      - School Efficiency Reviews for Virginia Education (SERVE), 2002-2003 (part one) (Box 122, Folder 3)
      - School Efficiency Reviews for Virginia Education (SERVE), 2002-2003 (part two) (Box 122, Folder 4)
      - School Efficiency Reviews for Virginia Education (SERVE), 2002-2003 (part three) (Box 122, Folder 5)
      - School Efficiency Reviews for Virginia Education (SERVE), 2002-2003 (part four) (Box 122, Folder 6)
      - School Efficiency Reviews, 2003 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Work Plans and Reports, 2003-2005
      - Education for a Lifetime, Work Plans, 6 November 2003 (Box 123, Folder 2)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Work Plans and Status Reports, 2003-2004 (part one) (Box 123, Folder 3)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Work Plans and Status Reports, 2003-2004 (part two) (Box 123, Folder 4)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Work Plans and Status Reports, 2003-2004 (part three) (Box 123, Folder 5)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Higher Education Plan, 2003 (Box 123, Folder 6)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Higher Education Plan, 2003-2004 (Box 137, Folder 1)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Education Plan K-12, 2003 (part one) (Box 124, Folder 1)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Education Plan K-12, 2003 (part two) (Box 124, Folder 2)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Education Plan K-12, 2003 (part three) (Box 124, Folder 3)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Records, 2005 (Box 124, Folder 4)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Records, 2005 (Box 124, Folder 5)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Budget Material, 2005 (part one) (Box 125, Folder 1)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Budget Material, 2005 (part two) (Box 125, Folder 2)
      - Education for a Lifetime, Miscellaneous, 2003-2005 (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - Subseries VI.C. The Governor's Partnership for Achieving Successful Schools (PASS), 2002-2005., Extent: 1.05 cubic feet. (Box 125-128)
    This subseries is housed in four boxes and is arranged by topic. The Governor's Partnership for Achieving Successful Schools (PASS) initiative, started by Governor Mark R. Warner in July 2002, was a statewide partnership with business and community leaders, state educators, and local school and government officials to boost student achievement in Virginia's lowest academically performing schools on Virginia's Standards of Learning (SOL). The majority of this material belonged to Deputy Secretary of Education Sarah Finley. Subseries contains articles, agendas, correspondence, e-mail, meeting notes, reports, memorandums, presentations, and press releases.
    Noteable records include: notes from meetings with the Governor, 2002; development of PASS initiative (Box 126, Folder 5) and PASS Reports, 2003-2005 (Box 127-128).
    - SOLAR/PASSMARK, 2002-2003
      - Records, 2002-2003 (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - Mentoring/Tutoring, 2002-2003
      - Records, 2002-2003 (part one) (Box 125, Folder 5)
      - Records, 2002-2003 (part two) (Box 126, Folder 1)
      - Records, 2002-2003 (part three) (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - PASS, 2002-2003
      - Records, 2002-2003 (part one) (Box 126, Folder 3)
      - Records, 2002-2003 (part two) (Box 126, Folder 4)
      - Records, 2002-2003 (part three) (Box 126, Folder 5)
      - PASS videotape, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 6)
      - Records, 2002-2003 (part four) (Box 127, Folder 1)
      - Records, 2003 (part five) (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - PASS Reports, 2003-2005
      - Records, 2004 (Box 127, Folder 3)
      - PASS Initiative Compliance Report, City of Richmond, 7 March 2003 (Box 127, Folder 4)